Saving The World... One Homework Assignment At A Time.
Sky High is a adventure, comedy, family film directed by Mike Mitchell.
Set in a world where superheroes are commonly known and accepted, young Will Stronghold, the son of the Commander
and Jetstream, tries to find a balance between being a normal teenager and an extraordinary being.
Will Stronghold, played by Michael Angarano.
Gwen Grayson / Royal Pain, played by Mary Elizabeth Winstead.
Steve Stronghold / The Commander, played by Kurt Russell.
Josie Stronghold / Jetstream, played by Kelly Preston.
Layla Williams, played by Danielle Panabaker.
Coach Boomer, played by Bruce Campbell.
Sky High is a 2005 American superhero comedy film directed by Mike Mitchell, and written by
Paul Hernandez, and Kim Possible creators Bob Schooley and Mark McCorkle.
The film stars Kelly Preston, Michael Angarano, Danielle
Panabaker, Mary Elizabeth Winstead and Kurt Russell.
It follows Will Stronghold (Angarano), the son of two superheroes, who is
enrolled in an airborne high school for teenage superheroes.
As his dormant superpowers manifest, he struggles to maintain his relationships with his old friends,
learns of a threat from a mysterious supervillain, and searches for the girl of his dreams.
The film was theatrically released by Buena Vista Pictures Distribution on July 29, 2005, and
grossed $86.4 million worldwide against a production budget of $35 million.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and audiences during its
original theatrical run and has since been recognized as a cult film.
The film explores themes of high school,
friendship, mission, superhero, loyalty.
The tone is lighthearted.